

# **Flight Certification**

- EASA-FCL PPL(A) Private Pilot License
- EASA-SFCL SPL Glider Pilot License
- Aerobatic Rating
- Night Rating
- Tailwheel Endorsement

# **Technical Skills**

- Python
- Matlab
- CATIA V5
- Solidworks
- Ansys

# Language

German

English

French

Dutch



# Contact

#### **Phone**

+49 176 482 40 763

#### **Address**

Budapester Str. 51 20359 Hamburg, Germany

#### **Email**

schmidt.julian@freenet.de

### LinkedIn

in/Julian-Schmidt



# Julian Schmidt

## Aerospace / Industrial Engineer and Pilot

With a background in Aerospace and Industrial Engineering, I specialize in areas such as aerodynamics and flight mechanics, as well as controls and systems design. As a pilot, I possess practical experience with avionics and autopilot systems, whereas my involvement in the airline industry has equipped me with knowledge of airline flight operations.

## **Education**

2021 - 2023

DTU - Technical University of Denmark

## MSc. Industrial Engineering and Management

During my studies, I joined the GENESIS project as part of the Clean Sky 2 initiative of the EU, where I researched the application of hydrogen as aviation fuel. I am writing my Master's thesis on the topic, where I build models for the demand estimation of hydrogen at European airports in the 2030-2050 period and assess the sustainability of the according supply chains.

Specialization: Project Management, Entrepreneurship, Life Cycle Assessment

2014 - 2019

TU Delft - Delft University of Technology

## **BSc.** Aerospace Engineering

In my thesis project I investigated the potential for increased efficiency of a legacy A320 wing through multidisciplinary optimisation of modifications for the aerodynamic and structural design. Nest to my studies I had the function as teaching assistent for Engineering Mechanics and Thermodynamics, and acted as a bodywork engineer in the Forze Hydrogen Electric Racing Team.

Specialization: Aerodynamics, Structural Design and Numerical Optimization

# **Experience**

O 2022 - now SATAIR A/S

## **Process and Performance Management**

To ensure compliance with internal practices and facilitate the auditing for ISO certification, I have tracked the processes for customer interaction in the COF department. As part of the integration between SATAIR Market and AIRBUS Spares, I have supported the team in laying out the milestones for the AIRBUS OnePortal project.

2021 - 2022

EnergyNest AS

## **Sales Consultant**

I have performed business development and sales activities within the German-speaking market. Here I identified the chemical and metals processing industry as the key targets for the company's industrial heat storage solution. Within these groups, I initiated the sales process which resulted in new customer acquisition.

2019 - 2020

Swiss International Air Lines AG

## **Student Pilot**

As a pilot student for Swiss International Air Lines I trained with Lufthansa Aviation Training Switzerland to obtain the EASA-FCL ATPL(A) pilot's license. Following the effects of Corona on the airline industry, training activities were halted in late 2020.